Kabir Abdulmajeed

Systems Engineer · Al. ML, DL, Robotics

15, Leora Court Richmond Hill, L4C 7N3, Ontario, Canada

□ (+966) 506138685 | 🗷 kbmajeed1@gmail.com | 🌴 kbmajeed.github.io | 🖸 kbmajeed | 🛅 kbmajeed

"Interested in intelligence and autonomy for different systems"

Summary

Current Co-founder & Software Engineer in start-up company PLAT Corp. 5+ years experience specializing in backend/infrastructure, web development and computer security. Super nerd who loves Vim, Linux and OS X and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Work Experience

ROSEN Dubai, UAE

SENSORS AND ALGORITHMS ENGINEER

Jul. 2018 - PRESENT

- Implemented RESTful API server for car rental booking application (CARPLAT in Google Play).
- Built and deployed overall service infrastructure utilizing Docker container, CircleCI, and several AWS stack(Including EC2, ECS, Route 53, S3, CloudFront, RDS, ElastiCache, IAM), focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.
- · Developed an easy-to-use Payment module which connects to major PG(Payment Gateway) companies in Korea.

Alcatel-Lucent Lagos, Nigeria

3G UMTS ENGINEER

Feb. 2011 - Aug. 2011

- Lead engineer on agent-less backtracking system that can discover client device's fingerprint(including public and private IP) independently of the Proxy, VPN and NAT.
- Implemented a distributed web stress test tool with high anonymity.
- · Implemented a military cooperation system which is web based real time messenger in Scala on Lift.

Osun State University Osun, Nigeria

GRADUATE ASSISTANT

Aug. 2013 - Dec. 2013

Dec. 2013 - Feb. 2014

- Developed in Cocos2d-x an action puzzle game(Dragon Buster) targeting U.S. market.
- Implemented API server which is communicating with game client and In-App Store, along with two other team members who wrote the game logic and designed game graphics.
- Won the 2nd prize in final evaluation.

Abike Memorial Clinics Kwara, Nigeria

• Developed a proxy drive smartphone application which connects proxy driver and customer.

• Implemented overall Android application logic and wrote API server for community service, along with lead engineer who designed bidding protocol on raw socket and implemented API server for bidding.

SAMSUNG Electronics S.Korea

FREELANCE PENETRATION TESTER

Sep. 2013, Mar. 2011 - Oct. 2011

- · Conducted penetration testing on SAMSUNG KNOX, which is solution for enterprise mobile security.
- Conducted penetration testing on SAMSUNG Smart TV.

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

2013	Runner-Up, National Budding Engineers and Scientists Award	Federal Ministry of Education, Abuja,
		Nigeria
2013	Pro-Chancellor's Award, Convocation ceremony, Osun State University	Osun, Nigeria
2013	Vice-Chancellor's Award, Convocation ceremony, Osun State University	Osun, Nigeria
2012	6th Place , SECUINSIDE Hacking Competition World Final	Seoul, S.Korea

DOMESTIC

2015	3rd Place , WITHCON Hacking Competition Final	Seoul, S.Korea
2013	Silver Prize, KISA HDCON Hacking Competition Final	Seoul, S.Korea

Presentation

6th CodeEngn (Reverse Engineering Conference)

Seoul, S.Korea

PRESENTER FOR < DEFCON 20TH: THE WAY TO GO TO LAS VEGAS>

Jul. 2012

• Introduced CTF(Capture the Flag) hacking competition and advanced techniques and strategy for CTF

Writing_

A Guide for Developers in Start-up

Facebook Page

FOUNDER & WRITER

Jan. 2015 - PRESENT

• Drafted daily news for developers in Korea about IT technologies, issues about start-up.

AhnLab S.Korea

Undergraduate Student Reporter

Oct. 2012 - Jul. 2013

• Drafted reports about IT trends and Security issues on AhnLab Company magazine.

Program Committees

2016 **Problem Writer**, 2016 CODEGATE Hacking Competition World Final

S Korea

2013 Organizer & Co-director, 1st POSTECH Hackathon

S.Korea

Education

POSTECH(Pohang University of Science and Technology)

Pohang, S.Korea

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Mar. 2010 - Exp. Aug. 2017

• Got a Chun Shin-Il Scholarship which is given to promising students in CSE Dept.

Extracurricular Activity

PoApper (Developers' Network of POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea

CORE MEMBER & PRESIDENT AT 2013

Jun. 2010 - PRESENT

- Reformed the society focusing on software engineering and building network on and off campus.
- Proposed various marketing and network activities to raise awareness.

PLUS (Laboratory for UNIX Security in POSTECH)

Pohang, S.Korea

MEMBER

Sep. 2010 - Oct. 2011

- Gained expertise in hacking & security areas, especially about internal of operating system based on UNIX and several exploit techniques.
- Participated on several hacking competition and won a good award.
- Conducted periodic security checks on overall IT system as a member of POSTECH CERT.
- Conducted penetration testing commissioned by national agency and corporation.